# João Pedro Peters Barbosa

### **BRIEF**

Power Systems Electrical Engineer, obtaining bachelor's (2021) and master's (2023) degrees from the Federal University of Juiz de Fora (UFJF), Minas Gerais. He has programming experience in different programming languages and also modeling and simulation skills in software related to Electric Power Systems.

He served as a research student in different projects throughout the undergraduate course and, still as an undergraduate student, carried out an academic exchange semester at Temple University, Philadelphia. He is currently pursuing Doctorate degree opportunities.

Adventurous in programming, following software engineering best practices to improve computational skills. He doesn't mind making mistakes and always seeks to promote a safe work environment, valuing collaboration between peers.

**SOCIAL** LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/joaoppeters/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/joaoppeters/</a>

GitHub: <a href="https://www.github.com/joaoppeters">https://www.github.com/joaoppeters</a>

#### **EXPERIENCES**

## May 2021 – May 2023 Graduate Research Assistant, UFJF

Juiz de Fora, MG

• Research development on electrical equipment modeling and simulation, considering the Smooth Power Flow formulation and its impacts on the voltage stability of electrical power systems. Paper presented, published, and awarded at SBSE2022.

## Mar 2020 – Apr 2021 Undergraduate Research Assistant, UFJF

Juiz de Fora, MG

- Research development in the area of Distributed Energy Resources (DERs) to provide new services to the electricity grid.
- Research project partnership between UFJF and PETROBRAS.

#### Aug 2018 – Jul 2019 Undergraduate Research Assistant, UFJF

Juiz de Fora, MG

• Research development in the area of current control in static buck-boost converters connected to the network, applying PID controlling techniques on a laboratory prototype.

## Aug 2017 – Jul 2018 Undergraduate Research Assistant, UFJF

Juiz de Fora, MG

• Research development in the area of current control in static converters connected to photovoltaic panel systems. Article published in IEEEXplore magazine and awarded project at COBEP2017.

Aug 2016 – Jul 2017 Undergraduate Research Assistant, UFJF

Juiz de Fora, MG

• Research development in the application of sorting methods for MMC modules.

**EDUCATION** 

May 2021 – May 2023 Masters in Science – Energy Systems, UFJF

Juiz de Fora, MG

GPA: 3.75/4.0

Aug 2015 – Apr 2021 Power Systems Electrical Engineering Undergraduate,

Juiz de Fora, MG

**UFJF** 

IRA: 78.47/100

Aug 2019 – Dez 2019 UFJF Academic Exchange Semester, Temple University

Philadelphia, PA

GPA: 3.74/4.0

Jul 2018 – Dez 2018 Technical Qualification, SENAI

Juiz de Fora, MG

**SKILLS** 

Leadership and Teamwork Microsoft Office, Latex

Organization and Efficiency Python, MatLab, C, C++

Flexibility and Adaptability ANAREDE, ANAFAS, ANTEM

Analytical skills OpenDSS, PSIM, OpenModelica

Problem-solving Git, GitHub

**LANGUAGES** 

Portuguese Native French Basic

**English** Fluent German Basic

Spanish Basic

**CERTIFICATES** 

2023 Scientific Computing with Python – freeCodeCamp

2021 Graduate Record Examinations (GRE) – Educational Testing Services (ETS)

**TOEFL iBT – Educational Testing Services (ETS)** 

2020 Data Analysis with Python – freeCodeCamp

2020	Introduction to Git and GitHub – Coursera
2019	Modeling and Simulation of Distribution Systems Using OpenDSS – UFJF
2016	Certificate of Advanced English (CAE) – University of Cambridge
2014	First Certificate of English (FCE) – University of Cambridge

REWAR	DS		
2022	Best Article Master's Category	IX Simpósio Brasileiro de	
		Sistemas Elétricos (SBSE)	
	Avaliação e aprimoramento de metodologias para representa fluxo de potência	ntação de CER no problema de	
2017	Best Article Undergraduate's Category	XIV Congresso Brasileiro	
		de Eletrônica de Potência	
		(COBEP)	
	Design and implementation of a predictive current controller applied to regulate a battery bank's power flow connected to a DC microgrid		
2016	Best Article Undergraduate's Category	XXII Seminário de Iniciação	
	Cien	tífica da UFJF (SEMIC/UFJF)	
	Síntese de conversores MMC para aplicação em sistemas de geração fotovoltaicos e sistemas de transmissão em corrente contínua		
SCIENT	IFIC PUBLICATIONS		
2022	Avaliação e aprimoramento de metodologias para	IX Simpósio Brasileiro de	
	representação de CER no problema de fluxo de potência	Sistemas Elétricos (SBSE)	
2020	Síntese de conversores MMC para aplicação em sistemas	PRINCIPIA, v.19	
	de geração fotovoltaicos e sistemas de transmissão em		
	corrente contínua		
2017	Design and implementation of a predictive current controller	XIV Congresso Brasileiro	
	applied to regulate a battery bank's power flow connected to	de Eletrônica de Potência	
	a DC microgrid	(COBEP)	

### **PROJECTS**

**PyANA:** development of Python code to support students and researchers in studies of steady state analysis of electrical power systems, based on reading data from ANAREDE files.

## **INTERESTS**

**Electrical Power Systems:** static and transient analysis, voltage stability, mathematical modeling of electrical equipment, operation, optimization, planning, distributed energy resources

Computational Programming: online learning, reinforcement learning, optimization techniques, software engineering best practices, open-source project development, machine learning, artificial intelligence

#### OTHER RELEVANT INFORMATION

- Member of the IEEE Power and Energy Society (IEEE PES) since 2023
- Member of the Sociedade Brasileira de Automática (SBA) since 2022
- Member of the Conselho Regional de Engenharia e Agronomia de Minas Gerais (CREA-MG) since 2021
- Member of the Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) since 2020